(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-21T00:43:46.066133",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
絶対的 天音かなた 卒業LIVE
Absolute: Amane Kanata Graduation LIVE
絶対的シャール 卒業LIVE
[Absolute Shaaru Graduation LIVE]
出会えた
We met...
奇跡に
...and it's a miracle...
もう息が止まりそうだよ
...I feel like my breath is about to stop.
荒野のピース
[Piece of the Wilderness]
何を見ているの
What are you looking at
どこまでも
with those endlessly...
澄んだ瞳で
...clear eyes?
二人だけ伝われる
In a world where only the two of us can connect,
世界できっと
surely...
すべてが今始まるから
...everything is starting now.
君に
To you...
会うために
...to meet you...
生まれたと
...I was born...
伝えたいんだ
...I want to tell you.
そよ風も眼差しも
The gentle breeze, your gaze...
視線も全部
...even your looks, everything...
ヒリヒリする
...turns into a tingling...
声になるのさ ずっと
...voice forever.
君をそばに感じる
I feel you close to me.
濁りのない
These pure...
透き通る気持ちは
...transparent feelings...
引き換えるものなんてない
...there's nothing to trade them for.
二人きり
Just the two of us...
未来さえ飛べるんだ
...can fly even into the future.
Woo...
La la la...
どこへ行くの？
Where are you going?
小さな
My small...
自分に
...self...
涙溢れるけど
...is overflowing with tears, but...
走り出せる
...I can start running.
もしも
If...
はぐれたら
...we get separated...
体ごと
...I will take you...
連れてってあげる
...body and soul with me.
花びら
Turning into...
たった一枚の
...just a single flower petal's...
姿になって
...form...
君の愛求めて
...seeking your love...
旅するよ ずっと
...I will journey forever.
君は
You...
守られて
...are protected...
汚れない
...by pure...
透き通る気持ちが
...transparent feelings...
時は超えて
...and transcending time...
呼び合う
...we call out to each other.
二人きり
Just the two of us...
未来へと
...towards the future...
飛び立つんだ
...will fly away.
出会えた
We met...
奇跡に
...and it's a miracle...
もう息が止まりそうだよ
...I feel like my breath is about to stop.
繋いだ
Holding...
その手に
...your hand...
少し強くなれる気がする
...I feel like I can become a little stronger.
出会えた
We met...
奇跡に
...and it's a miracle...
もう息が止まりそうだよ
...I feel like my breath is about to stop.
明日も
Tomorrow...
未来も
...and the future too...
ただどうしようもなく好きだよ
...I just love you beyond help.
Oh oh oh...
ピースサイン
[Title: Peace Sign]
いつか僕らの上をスレスレに
One day, grazing right above us,
通り過ぎていったあの飛行機を
that airplane flew past...
不思議なくらいに憶えている
I remember it so clearly, it's strange,
意味もないのに なぜか
even though it has no meaning, somehow.
不甲斐なくて泣いた日の夜に
On the night of the day I cried out of helplessness,
ただ強くなりたいと願ってた
I was just wishing to become stronger.
そのために必要な勇気を
And the courage needed for that,
探し求めていた
I was searching for it.
残酷な運命が定まってるとして<
Even if a cruel fate has been set,
それがいつの日か僕の前に現れるとして
and even if it appears before me one day,
ただ一瞬 この一瞬 息ができるなら
if I can breathe for just a moment, this single moment,
どうでもいいと思えた その心を
I felt like nothing else mattered, that heart...
もう一度
Once more,
遠くへ行け遠くへ行けと
calling me to "go further, go further,"
僕の中で誰かが歌う
someone is singing inside of me.
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
With a passion so helpless,
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と
so that you, who always had swollen eyes,
悲しまないように笑える
can laugh and never be sad again.
そんなヒーローになるための歌
This is the song to become that kind of hero.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Farewell, raise your hand with a peace sign!
転がっていくストーリーを
To our rolling, unfolding story.
守りたいだなんて言えるほど
To the point where I can say I want to protect you,
君が弱くはないのわかってた
I knew you weren't weak.
それ以上に僕は弱くてさ
But even more than that, I was the weak one,
君が大事だったんだ
and you were just so precious to me.
「独りで生きていくんだ」なんてさ<
Saying "I'm going to live all alone,"
口をついて叫んだあの日から
ever since that day I blurted out and screamed those words,
変わっていく僕を笑えばいい
you can laugh at how much I'm changing,
独りが怖い僕を
at me, who is actually afraid of being alone.
蹴飛ばして噛み付いて息もできなくて
Kicking, biting, and unable to even breathe,
騒ぐ頭と腹の奥がぐしゃぐしゃになったって
even if my noisy head and the pit of my stomach get all jumbled up,
衒いも外連も消えてしまうくらいに<
to the point where all pretense and theatricality disappear,
今は触れていたいんだ 君の心に
right now, I just want to touch your heart.
僕たちは きっといつか遠く離れた
We will surely, one day, reach out
太陽にすら手が届いて
even to the far-off sun,
夜明け前を手に入れて笑おう
and grab the dawn before we laugh.
そうやって青く燃える色に染まり
Dyeing ourselves in that blue, burning color,
おぼろげな街の向こうへ
beyond the hazy streets,
手をつないで走っていけるはずだ
we should be able to run hand-in-hand.
君と未来を盗み描き出す
Stealing and sketching the future with you,
陰りのないストーリーを
to make a flawless story.
カサブタだらけ荒れくれた日々が
The rough days covered in scabs,
削り削られ擦り切れた今が
the present, shaved down and worn away...
君の言葉で蘇る
They come back to life with your words,
鮮やかにも 現れていく
appearing vividly before me.
蛹のままで眠る魂を
My soul sleeping like a chrysalis,
食べかけのまま捨てたあの夢を
that half-eaten, abandoned dream...
もう一度取り戻せ
I will reclaim it once more!
Oh oh oh...
もう一度
Once more,
遠くへ行け遠くへ行けと
calling me to "go further, go further,"
僕の中で誰かが歌う
someone is singing inside of me.
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
With a passion so helpless,
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と
so that you, who always had swollen eyes,
悲しまないように笑える
can laugh and never be sad again.
そんなヒーローになるための歌
This is the song to become that kind of hero.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Farewell, raise your hand with a peace sign!
転がっていくストーリーを
To our rolling, unfolding story.
君と未来を盗み描き出す
Stealing and sketching the future with you,
陰りのないストーリーを
to make a flawless story.
考えたってわからないし
I've thought about it, but I still don't understand,
青空の下、君を待った
so I waited for you under the blue sky.
風が吹いた正午
At noon, when the wind blew,
昼下がりを抜け出す想像
imagining escaping into the afternoon.
ねえ、これからどうなるんだろうね
Hey, what will happen from here on out?
進め方教わらないんだよ
I was never taught how to proceed.
君の目を見た
I looked into your eyes,
何も言えず僕は歩いた
and unable to say anything, I walked on.
だから僕は音楽を辞めた
[Title: Because I Quit Music]
考えたってわからないし<
I've thought about it, but I still don't understand,
青春なんてつまらないし
and youth is just so boring anyway.
辞めたはずのピアノ
The piano I was supposed to have quit,
机を弾く癖が抜けない
yet I can't break the habit of tapping my desk.
ねえ、将来何しているんだろうね
Hey, what will I be doing in the future?
音楽はしてないといいな
I hope I'm not making music.
困らないでよ
Don't look so troubled.
心はどうだ
How is your heart?
体に
Within your body,
一つず
one by one...
引いても
...even if I drew a line...
どうしても消えなかった
...it wouldn't disappear no matter what.
今更なんだから
It's too late now, so...
なぁ、もう
...look,
思い出すな
don't remind me anymore!
間違ってるんだよ わかってないよ、あんたら人間も
You've got it wrong! You just don't get it, any of you humans.
本当も愛も世界も苦しさも人生も
The truth, love, the world, pain, and life itself...
どうでもいいよ
...I don't care about any of it.
正しいかどうか知りたいのだって防衛本能だ
Wanting to know right from wrong is just a self-preservation instinct.
考えたんだ あんたのせいだ
I thought about it, and it's all your fault.
考えたってわからないが、本当に年老いたくないんだ
Even if I think about it, I don't get it, but I really don't want to grow old.
いつか死んだらって思うだけで胸が空っぽになるんだ
Just the thought of dying someday makes me feel completely hollow inside.
将来何してるだろうって 大人になったらわかったよ
I wondered what I'd be doing in the future, and now that I'm grown up, I know...
何もしてないさ
...I'm not doing anything at all.
幸せな
Why is it...
顔
...that I hate people...
した人が憎いのは
...who wear happy faces?
どう割り切ったらいいんだ
How am I supposed to rationalize this?
満たされない頭の奥の
Deep inside my unsatisfied head lies...
化け物みたいな劣等感
...a monster-like inferiority complex.
間違ってないよ なぁ、何だかんだあんたら人間だ
I'm not wrong. After all, you're all just humans.
愛も救いも優しさも根拠がないなんて気味が悪いよ
It's sickening that love, salvation, and kindness have no basis.
ラブソングなんかが痛いのだって防衛本能だ
The pain from a love song is just a self-preservation instinct.
どうでもいいか あんたのせいだ
Whatever. It's all your fault.
考えたってわからないし 生きてるだけでも苦しいし
Even if I think about it, I don't get it, and just living is painful.
音楽とかもうからなそうだし
It's not like music is going to make any money anyway,
歌詞とか適当でもいいよ
so even sloppy lyrics are fine.
どうでもいいんだ
I don't care about anything anymore.
間違ってないだろ
I'm not wrong, am I?
間違ってないよな
I'm not wrong, right?
I can't be wrong...
間違ってるんだよ わかってるんだ あんたら人間も
I am wrong, and I know it! But so are you humans.
本当も愛も救いも優しさも人生も
The truth, love, salvation, kindness, and life...
どうでもいいんだ
...I don't care about any of it.
正しい答えが言えないのだって防衛本能だ
Being unable to give the correct answer is just a self-defense instinct.
どうでもいいや あんたのせいだ
Whatever. It's all your fault.
僕だって信念があった
I used to have beliefs too.
今じゃゴミみたいな思い出だ
Now, they're just garbage-like memories.
何度も君を描いた
I wrote about you over and over again.
売れることこそがどうでもよかったんだ
I didn't care at all whether it would sell.
本当だ 本当なんだ
It's true. It's really true.
昔はそうだった
That's how it used to be.
だから僕は
That's why I...
音楽を辞めた
...gave up on music.
今なんじゃない？
Is this the right time?
メラメラとたぎれ
Let it boil and burn like a flame!
眠っているだけの正義
This justice that's just been sleeping.
こんな僕も
Even someone like me...
君の
...wants to be...
ヒーローになりたいのさ
...your hero!
かっこいい君には
To someone as cool as you,
僕じゃ頼りないのかななんて
I wonder if I seem a bit unreliable.
そりゃそうだよな だって
Well, that makes sense, because...
今もこうして迷っている
...even now, I'm still lost like this.
手を取ってくれないか
Won't you take my hand?
ギブアンドテイクさ
It's all give and take.
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were once a hero to me.
今なんじゃない？
Is this the right time?
メラメラとたぎる
It's boiling and burning like a flame!
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice lurking inside someone like me...
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
...is driven by an uncontrollable impulse.
ほら気づけば手を握っている
Look, before I knew it, I was holding your hand!
一体全体
Tell me, why...
そんなに荷物を背負い込んで
...are you carrying so much baggage...
どこへ行くの
...and where are you going?
ねえねえ待って 僕にちょっと預けてみては
Hey, wait, why don't you try letting me carry some of it?
信じてばかりの僕と
Between me, who does nothing but believe,
信じることが怖い君と
and you, who are afraid of believing...
どちらが正しいのか なんて
Which is right?
誰にもわからないさ
No one knows.
ラララ...
Lalala...
僕らだけの世界
The world only for us,
ラララ...
Lalala...
ギブアンドテイクさ
it's give and take.
ラララ...
Lalala...
補い合えた暁には同じ夢を見たい
I want to have the same dream at the complemented dawn.
君はかっこいいと苦しめて ひとりぼっちにさせたのは
Distressing you that you're cool, leaving you alone...
少し僕のせいなんだよな ごめんね
...was also my fault, I know, I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But what you should watch is the "real" world.
いまこそ僕が助けるんだ
Now is the time to save you.
抱えないで 信じて 頼ってほしいんだ
Don't take it all on yourself, please believe and rely on me.
いまなんじゃない？
Is this the right time?
メラメラとたぎる こんな僕にも潜む正義が
Burning like a flame, justice lurked even in myself.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて ほら気づけば手を握っている<
Beaten by an overwhelming impulse, look, I realized I'm holding hands.
ほっとけない
I can't leave you alone.
そんなに荷物をしょい込んでどこへ行くの
Where are you going carrying so much on your back?
ほんのちょっと僕にちょっと預けてみては
Why don't you leave some to me, just a little bit?
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero.
ラララ...
Lalala...
はい！皆さん！
Yes! Everyone!
とうとう始まってしまいました！
It has finally begun!
天音かなた卒業ライブ！と、
Amane Kanata's Graduation Live!
いうことでですね、
And with that,
こちら、ハッシュタグが、
for the hashtag here,
あの、シャープ天音かなた卒業ライブでございますので、ぜひこちらよろしくお願いいたします！
it's #AmaneKanataGraduationLive, so please use it!
1曲目に歌った「今宵の月のように」は、実は初配信で歌おうか悩んでいた楽曲だったので、
The first song I sang, "Koyoi no Tsuki no Yō ni," was actually a song I hesitated to sing for my debut stream,
ここで歌えてすごく良かった！ありがとう！
so I'm really glad I could sing it here! Thank you!
えー、小さい頃からね、ヒロインよりヒーローになりたいっていう、僕、タイプだったので、そういった楽曲をたくさん歌わせていただきました。
Since I was little, I was the type who wanted to be a hero rather than a heroine, so I sang a lot of those kinds of songs.
次からは、ありがとね、みんな、拍手もありがとう。次からは、
Next up... thank you everyone, and thank you for the applause. Next up...
ロックで感情ぶつけていくような歌に、挑戦しますんで。ちょっとマイクが、挑戦しますんで！
I'll be challenging myself with rock songs to throw all my emotions out. Wait, the mic... I'm going to challenge myself!
聴いてください、劣等上等！
Please listen to "Bring It On"!
劣等上等 BRING IT ON
Bring it on, being inferior is no problem!
列島上々 不眠日本
The islands are in high spirits, sleepless Japan!
子供騙しのマセマティカ ばれてんだって そんなプライドがない！
They've seen through your child's play mathematics! You've got no pride like that!
ご立派警鐘気取りで
With your grand warning-bell airs,
高みの見物ばかりじゃつまんねぇ
only looking down from above is so boring!
ほらもっと 間違って上等
Look, making more mistakes is even better!
退屈に手をかけて
So put an end to this boredom!
んなわけないじゃん？
No way!
やっぱあたしは こんなところじゃ終われない
After all, there's no way I can end in a place like this!
ぬるくて気が触れそう
It's so lukewarm I'm about to go mad!
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさようなら
Goodbye to playing pretend and playing roles!
ずっとこのままでいようねってさ
Saying "let's stay like this forever"...
いらないよ
I don't need that!
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da-da-da, I'm going to become an adult!
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Now, sorting through the sour and the sweet,
パッパッパ 変わる時代
Pa-pa-pa, in this changing era,
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう<
surely it's not all bad things!
過去も 罪も 罰も すべて
The past, the sins, the punishments, all of them...
素手で、愛で 生き抜いてやり返すわ
with bare hands, with love, I'll survive and strike back!
yeah 挑発 あたしたちは no doubt
Yeah, provocation, we are no doubt!
緑のアイツにばっか構ってねぇ
We're not just fussing over that green guy!
さぁ burn up
Come on, burn up!
いつになったら貰える合格
When will we ever get a passing grade?
赤ペン入れてよどこがダメなんですか
Grade me in red, what exactly is wrong with me?
酒 女 金 ドラッグ
Booze, girls, money, drugs...
やっちゃってコンプラ
doing them all and breaking compliance!
Ah...
冗談じゃんブラックジョーク
Just kidding, black joke!
中指立てたくなるような事情
There are so many situations
ありすぎて指が足りねえから
that make me want to flip the middle finger, I don't have enough fingers,
hands up
so hands up!
最低? もともとだろ bring it on
The worst? I've always been that way, bring it on!
「まあまあ」なんか要らない
I don't need "so-so" things.
欲しがります死ぬまでは
I will keep wanting until I die.
伸びた背丈 育った街に投げキッス
Now that I've grown up, I blow a kiss to the city I was raised in.
見せ場はこっから 覚悟しとけよ
The real show starts now, you better be ready.
ダッダッダ 僕ら大人になる
Da-da-da, we are growing up.
カウンター狙い 最低な日々に
Aiming for a counter-attack on these terrible days,
弾丸とかます一撃
I'll blast them with a single bullet of a blow!
誰も読めない先 まだあいこでしょ
No one can read the future, it's still a tie, isn't it?
素手で、生きて! 生き抜いて覆すよ
With my bare hands, live on! Survive and turn the tables!
Ah...
ばっかが譲れない
Only stupid things I won't back down on.
わかるか? あたしの美学
Do you understand? My aesthetic.
この馬鹿正直な拳ひとつが
This single, brutally honest fist...
(一途なんです)
(I am single-minded)
切り札
...is my trump card.
(愚直なんです)
(I am simple-mindedly honest)
がなる劣等 一抜けよサラバ!
Roaring out inferiority, I'll be the first to get out, farewell!
Ah--------!
Ah, oh, oh...
こんなもんじゃない
I'm not done yet!
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da-da-da, I will grow up.
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Now, tasting both the sweet and sour of life.
燦々 交わる未来
The brilliantly intersecting future.
もう子供じゃないのわかるでしょ
You can tell I'm not a child anymore, right?
時代 機会 待ってくれない
Time and opportunity won't wait for us.
素手で、捨て身で 生き抜いて上等だわ
With bare hands, throwing myself in, surviving is just fine!
Ah, ah, ah, oh...
愛ある時代!
An era full of love!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
それでは皆様 お先にbye, guys!
And with that, everyone, I'll say goodbye first, guys!
フロアが沸き上がりました
The floor has heated up!
ぼくらの16bit戦争 / 作詞・作曲: sasakure.UK
[Song: Our 16bit Warz / Lyrics & Composition: sasakure.UK]
どうしてこんな事になったんだ?
Why did it turn out like this?
誰も教えてちゃくれないんだ。
Nobody will tell me.
何がセイギだ 何がギセイだ
What is justice? What is sacrifice?
”秩序”は僕を裏切った
"Order" has betrayed me.
はじめは微さな孔だったんだ
At first, it was a tiny hole.
居心地だけは良かったのにな。
Though, at least, it was comfortable.
プロパガンダと呑めや詠えや、孔は次第に誇大化した
Singing and drinking to propaganda, the hole gradually expanded.
相対と絶対の飽和水蒸気圧
Relative and absolute saturation vapor pressure.
都合が善過ぎた大人達の都合に<
For the too-convenient convenience of adults,
ひとつ また ひとつと未来は過去を無視した
one after another, the future ignored the past.
65535 の テトラと ゼロ次元の 理想 抱えていてもなお
Even though I still hold 65535 tetras and a zero-dimensional ideal,
ひとつ また ひとつとエデンは姿を消した<
one after another, Edens vanished.
ぼくらの16bit戦争。
Our 16bit war.
イデアの波に蝕まれるな
Don't be eroded by the wave of ideas.
残された空間で僕は
In the remaining space, I
うかつに肘さえつけやしない
cannot even rest my elbows carelessly.
ぼくらの16bit戦争。
Our 16bit war.
アルトとエゴが交差する
Altruism and egoism intersect.
XYしか aiseナイ僕は
I, who can only love X and Y,
何を信じて生きれば良い?
what should I believe in to live on?
ドット包囲網をかいくぐる
Slipping through the dot dragnet,
レジスタンスらを一斉掃射
firing a sweep at the resistance,
無言圧力 数の暴力
silent pressure, violence of numbers,
自由はすでに亡くなった
freedom has already ceased to exist.
鋼に打ち込めよと
Shoot into the steel...
警告の警笛
A warning horn...
肩越しに響く矩形波の断末魔
Echoing over my shoulder, the terminal scream of a square wave.
アルカディアの鐘が鳴る日は来るのだろうか
Will the day ever come when the bells of Arcadia ring?
僕らの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war...
イデアの波に呑まれるな
...don't get swallowed up by the waves of ideas!
残された空間で
In the space left behind,
僕は今日もぐっすり眠りがしない
I can't sleep soundly today either.
僕らの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war...
アルトとエゴが交差する
...where alto and ego intersect.
ビットダウン ビットレートの積で
By the product of a downsampled bitrate,
僕は秩序を裏切らない
I will not betray the order.
僕らの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war...
世界を敵に回しても
...even if I make the world my enemy.
表現し得ないものが
The reality that things which cannot be expressed...
絆される現実が何より許せなかった
...are bound was more unforgivable than anything else.
僕らの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war.
はい！皆さんありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you very much, everyone!
ここにね、何があると思います？
What do you think is right here?
水！
Water!
今回は、あの、結構歌に集中するラインナップで来ましたけども、
This time, I went with a lineup that's pretty focused on singing, but...
トレンド1位って本当ですか、これ？
Is it true that we're trending at #1?
嘘かもしれませんけれども。本当かな？
It might be a lie, but... is it true?
ガチかも。
Maybe it's for real.
ありがとう、みんな！
Thank you, everyone!
ありがとう。「かっこいい」と言ってくれてるのを見ながら...
Thank you. Reading everyone calling me "cool"...
おい、メガホンマイクが手からすっぽ抜けかけましたよ！本当に。
Hey, the megaphone mic almost slipped right out of my hand! Seriously.
焦ったわ。
That was a scare.
ということでね、えっと、何かに挑んでいく曲みたいなのは好きなので、もともと。
So anyway, I've always liked songs about taking on challenges.
「劣等上等」と「ぼくらの16bit戦争」を歌わせていただきました！
So I sang "Bring It On" and "Our 16-Bit War"!
ね、すごい大好きなカッコいい楽曲たちなので、ぜひぜひ原曲もチェックしてみて下さい！
They're incredibly cool songs that I love, so please check out the original versions too!
ちょっと待って。僕、VTuberなんで着替えは何秒かかると思う？1秒だ！
Wait a sec. I'm a VTuber, so how many seconds do you think it takes me to change? One second!
ほれ！
Ta-da!
すごいやろ？
Amazing, right?
これがVTuber、バーチャルアイドルね！
This is what a VTuber, a virtual idol, can do!
では、このまま続けていくぞ！
Now, let's keep this going!
ローリンガール
[Song: Rolling Girl]
ロンリーガールはいつまでも届かない夢見て
A lonely girl is always dreaming dreams that won't come true,
騒ぐ頭の中を掻き回して、掻き回して。
churning, churning through the noise inside her head.
「問題ない。」と呟いて、言葉は失われた？
Muttering "I'm fine," have words failed her?
もう失敗、もう失敗。間違い探しに終われば、また、回るの！
A failure, a failure. Obsessing over her mistakes makes everything spin again!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、少女は言う 少女は言う
"I'll roll along today too," the girl said, the girl said,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
breathing life into her words!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready yet?"
「まだですよ、まだまだ先は見えないので。息を止めるの、今。」
"Not yet, we still can't see what's ahead. Hold your breath, for now."
ローリンガールの成れの果て 届かない、向こうの色
For the rolling girl's sad end, the colors beyond are out of reach...
重なる声と声を混ぜあわせて、混ぜあわせて。
blending, blending overlapping voices together.
重なる声と声を
The overlapping voices...
混ぜ合わせて、混ぜ合わせて
...blend together, blend together.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
"No problem," she muttered,
言葉は失われた？
but have the words been lost?
どうなったって良いんだってさ
She says she doesn't care what happens,
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと誘う、坂道
on the sloping path inviting her to make mistakes.
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
私をどうか転がしてと
"Please let me roll,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
無口に意味を重ねながら！
as she silently piles meanings!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready?"
「もう少し、
"Just a little more,
もうすぐ何か見えるだろうと。
soon I think I'll see something.
息を止めるの、今。」
I'm holding my breath now."
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I will roll again today,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
言葉に笑みを奏でながら！
playing a smile into her words!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready?"
「もう良いよ。
"You're ready now.
そろそろ君も疲れたろう、ね。」
You must be tired by now, right?"
息を止めるの、今。
I'm holding my breath now.
今度こそ
This time for sure,
生き返れない そう思った ベッドの中
I won't survive, so I thought inside my bed.
気付けばカーテンの隙間から
Before I knew it, through the gap in the curtains,
朝が「起きて」と教えてくれた
the morning told me, "wake up."
あぁ 生きていたと安堵
Ah, relief that I was alive.
あぁ 生きてしまったと絶望
Ah, despair that I ended up surviving.
まだやれるのかな まだやらなきゃなのかな
Can I still keep going? Do I still have to?
いっそ 灰になってしまえば
If only I could just turn to ash...
なんてね
...just kidding.
「私元気です。」そう言って
Saying, "I'm doing well,"
今日も笑って
I laugh again today,
心はガランドウで
while my heart is completely empty.
大袈裟な音がする
It makes an exaggerated sound.
あぁ 週末の鐘の音か
Ah, is that the sound of the weekend bells?
それでもこの声が
Even so, this voice,
それでもこの口が
even so, this mouth,
それでもこの喉が
even so, this throat,
千切れるくらい 叫ぶよ
will scream until it tears apart!
この腕が
These arms,
真っ白なこの羽が
these pure white wings,
僕のこの命が
this life of mine,
「生きたい」と歌っている
are singing, "I want to live!"
できるなら 愛されたい 許されたい
If possible, I want to be loved, to be forgiven,
ここにいたい 愛したい
I want to be here, I want to love.
誰も見ていない夢を見るよ
I'll dream a dream that nobody else is watching,
だから僕を見ていてよ
so please keep looking at me!
感情の 捨て方はさ
How do you throw away emotions?
粗大ゴミのシールを貼る
Just stick a bulky waste label on them.
本音はいつも強がりの裏
My true feelings are always behind my tough front,
潰れる音がするんだ
making a crushing sound.
あぁ 気付かれなかった
Ah, nobody noticed.
あぁ 気付いてほしかった
Ah, I wanted someone to notice.
それでも君が笑ってくれるならいっそ
Even so, if you will smile for me, I'd rather...
心を無くしてしまえば
...just lose my heart completely.
なんてね
...just kidding.
「叶わない」なんて
Thinking "it won't come true"...
一瞬でも思ったら負けだ
...even for a split second, means defeat.
「叶わない」なんて
Thinking "it won't come true"...
一瞬でもよぎったら辞めるの？
...even if it crosses your mind, will you quit?
何万の 諦める
Even if there are tens of thousands...
理由があったとして
...of reasons to give up,
たった一つの 勇気が
a single piece of courage...
この手の中にある
...is right here in my hand.
それでもこの声が
Even so, this voice,
それでもこの口が
even so, this mouth,
それでもこの喉が
even so, this throat,
千切れるくらい 叫ぶよ
will scream until it tears apart!
この腕が
These arms,
真っ白なこの羽が
these pure white wings,
僕のこの命が
this life of mine,
「生きたい」と歌っている
are singing, "I want to live!"
できるなら 愛されたい 許されたい
If possible, I want to be loved, to be forgiven,
ここにいたい 愛したい
I want to be here, I want to love.
誰も見ていない夢を見るよ
I'll dream a dream that nobody else is watching,
だから僕を見ていて
so please keep looking at me.
誰も見てない
No matter what anyone else sees...
夢を見せよう
...I'll show you a dream no one has ever seen.
だから
So...
僕を
...believe in...
信じて
...me!
はい！
Yes!
皆さん、今のは最後のオリジナル楽曲です！
Everyone, that was my final original song!
「誰も見てない夢を見ろ」というね、
It's called "Daremo Mitenai Yume wo Miro."
本日２４時にリリース！
It will be released today at 24:00!
わあ！こちらのジャケットをですね、頼りに探してくださいね、配信を。
Wow! Please look for this jacket art to find the stream.
いや、この曲あまりにも卒業ソングすぎるって思ったでしょ？
You probably thought, "This song is way too much of a graduation song," right?
これ実は、卒業決める前に作られていた曲で、
But actually, this song was made before my graduation was decided.
卒業決める前に、MVは明日ね、あの、明日の２０時、
And the MV will be released tomorrow, um, tomorrow at 20:00.
もう、かなたがいなくなっても予約投稿というものがある！
Even if I'm gone, there is a scheduled upload feature!
ネットには。ということで、明日の２０時に投稿されるんですが、
On the internet. So, it will be uploaded tomorrow at 20:00...
内容も実は、卒業を誰も知らずに作っているということで、
and the contents were actually made without anyone knowing about the graduation.
なんかこんな偶然の一致でそれっぽくなってしまいました。
Through some amazing coincidence, it ended up fitting perfectly.
それを踏まえてまた、「なんやねん」と思いながら聴いてください。
Keep that in mind and listen to it again while going, "What the heck?"
ヒゲドライバーさんにね、作詞作曲していただいて、
It was written and composed by Hige Driver-san.
アクマの声をいっぱい歌ったりしたんで、超嬉しかったです！ありがとうございました。
I got to sing a lot in that devilish voice, so I was super happy! Thank you very much.
そしてですね、お次はグッズを紹介させていただきます。こちら！
And next, let me introduce the merchandise. Here it is!
はい！天音かなた卒業グッズがもう出てます！
Yes! Amane Kanata's graduation merchandise is already available!
なんと出てる！ということで、それでは１つずつ見ていきましょう。まずは、こちら！
It's actually out! So, let's take a look at them one by one. First, this one!
はい、アクリルパネルです！かわいいでしょう？じゃん！
Yes, it's the acrylic panel! Isn't it cute? Tada!
こちらね、おしおママに想いをお伝えしたうえで、描き下ろしていただいたイラストになっております。
This is an illustration drawn by Oshio-mama after I shared my thoughts with her.
本当にね、みんなに対して最後は「笑顔かな」とか、
I really felt that at the end, I should face everyone with a smile,
青い薔薇というものを最初からモチーフ的に入れたりすることがあったので、
and since the blue rose has been used as a motif since the beginning,
こちらでまた入れていただきました。かわいいでしょう？
we had it included here as well. Isn't it pretty?
笑顔にしてもらいました。お次は、こちら！じゃん！
I asked for a smiling face. Next up is this! Tada!
じゃん！これ、これすごい！
Tada! This, this is amazing!
かなた＆こなたアクリルスタンドです！
It's the Kanata & Konata Acrylic Stand!
これもね、僕が本当にね、こなたという妹というものをぜひこの世に残して生きてえよ、ということで
Since I really wanted my younger sister Konata to be remembered in this world,
僕が欲しいがために生まれたグッズでございます。かわいいでしょう？
this piece of merch was born purely out of my own desire to have it. Cute, right?
エロいよな。
It's kind of sexy, isn't it?
ということで、次は、こちら！じゃん！
Moving on, next is this! Tada!
ボイスキーホルダーです！ボイスのね、６種は僕がオリジナル考えました。
It's a Voice Keychain! I came up with the 6 original voice lines myself.
オリジナルチームの、ヘイ！こんかなたーとか、だけれどさ。じゃん！
Our original team... like "Hey! Kon Kanata!" and so on. Tada!
で、このイラストもですね、僕、原案を書いて、プロがすごいよくしてくれましたね。
I drew the rough draft for this illustration, and the pros made it look amazing.
でも、分かるでしょう？かなたその絵柄って。皆さん、ありがとうございます。
But you can tell it's Kanata's art style, right? Thank you, everyone.
収録ボイスが届いてからの、お楽しみです。いっぱいポチポチしてください。
Please look forward to hearing the recorded voices. Press it lots of times!
そして最後のグッズは、こちら！じゃじゃん！
And the last piece of merch is... this! Tada!
アルティメットへい民認定書！
The Ultimate Heimin Certificate!
これは、最後まで応援してくれた究極のへい民、アルティメットへい民の認定書です。
This is a certificate for the ultimate Heimins who supported me to the very end.
シリアルナンバーが入っていて世界で１枚です。ちなみにちょっと、お買い得じゃねえや。
It has a serial number and is one of a kind. By the way, it's quite affordable—wait, not affordable...
手が届きやすいので、これだけでもぜひ皆さん、思い出によろしくお願いします。
It's easy to get, so I hope you'll grab it as a keepsake.
今までへい民じゃなかったけど、かなたーんって思った人もね、アルティメットへい民だから、あんたは。
Even if you weren't a Heimin before, if you're cheering for me now, you're an Ultimate Heimin too!
ということでですね、お次は、こちら特典ですね。
And with that, next is the purchase bonus.
はい、特典はポストカードになっております。
Yes, the bonus is a postcard.
数量限定が直筆サイン入りだったんですが、こちらはですね、１２月２４日の８時から発売開始しており、
The limited edition was hand-signed, and sales started on December 24th at 8:00.
もう、品切れ...ごめんなさい、完売しているんですけど、
And it's already sold out... I'm sorry about that,
フルセットのほうはまだありますので、箔押し複製サイン入ってますので、よろしくお願いします。
but the full set is still available and comes with a foil-stamped replica signature!
ちょっとね、このフルセット特典のほうは、「寂しいよ」っていう気持ちがちょっと溢れ出た感じになっております。
The art on this bonus postcard has a bit of a sentimental, "I'll miss you" feel to it.
はい、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
Yes, please check it out.
ふう、すげえ、汗かいた...
Phew, I'm sweating so much...
え、待って！何？
Wait, what?
かなた！かなた！
Kanata! Kanata!
ええええええええ！？
What on earth!?
待って、待って、ちょっと待って！うそ！
Wait, wait, hold on! No way!
サプライズ！サプライズできました！
Surprise! We pulled off a surprise!
卒業するんですけど！
I'm graduating, you know!
ええ？かなた！
What? Kanata!
ひどい！ひどいよ！
That's so mean!
一人で見せ場作ってたのに！
And I was making my big solo moment!
え、ゲストいないので...
Wait, I didn't have any guests...
いる、いる、いる、いる、いる！
We're here, we're here!
一人でやらせませんから！
We't won't let you do this alone!
嘘！本当に！？一人でやるって言ったのに！
No way! Really!? I said I would do it alone!
あ、人たちが来てる！
Ah, people are actually here!
来てる、来てる！
We're here!
本当だ！
It's true!
ころね、ラミィ、トワ、スバルがなんか...
Korone, Lamy, Towa, and Subaru...
来てくれました！
...have come to see me!
あんた歌上手くなったね！
Your singing has gotten so much better!
ええ！？ありがとう！
Really!? Thank you!
えー！
Whoa!
ちょっと、我々から渡したいものがありますよね？
Wait, we have something we want to give you, right?
何何何？マジで聞いてない、知らない！
What, what, what? Seriously, I haven't heard, I didn't know!
マジで言ってない、マジで言ってない！
We seriously didn't tell you, seriously!
え、何ですか？やだー！
Eh, what is it? No way!
泣かせないで、泣かせないで！
Don't make her cry, don't make her cry!
はい、どうぞ！
Here you go!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
持てないか、持てないよね。
Can you not hold it? You can't, right?
あ、すごい！
Ah, amazing!
これ、3人で選んだんだよ。
We three chose this together.
え、そうなの？
Eh, really?
そうです。
Yes, we did.
え、すごい！なんか、とても美しい薔薇みたいな感じの。
Eh, amazing! It looks like a very beautiful rose.
ちょっとね、バーチャル空間には映らないんだけど。
Well, it doesn't show up in the virtual space, but...
ちょっと映らないんですけど、私だけのものです、皆さん！
It doesn't show up, but it's mine only, everyone!
え、すごい！こんなにデカい花束もらったことない！
Eh, amazing! I've never received such a huge bouquet before!
あ、ええ...
Ah, sob...
じゃあ、一旦回収します。
Okay, we'll take it back for now.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
それとね、3人で寄せ書きも。
Also, a message card from the three of us.
え、ありがとう！嬉しい！
Eh, thank you! I'm so happy!
え、あかん。今見たら泣いちゃう。
Oh, no. If I look at it now, I'll cry.
泣いちゃうね。
You'll cry, right?
後で、後で。
Later, later.
本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much!
いや、待って。本当に嫌だ。
No, wait. I really don't want this to end.
本当に嫌だ。
We really don't want it either.
本当に。
Really...
やめる？やめるの、やめる？
Are you going to stop? Stop? Stop?
ここ、ここで。
Here, right here.
ここでやめて、大炎上する。
If you stop here, it'll cause a huge controversy.
3人も背負ってくれるってことで、一緒に。
Meaning you three will share the blame with me.
しょう、しょう、しょう。
Sure, sure, sure.
心強い！
How reassuring!
初配信、明日。
First stream tomorrow.
明日ね。
Tomorrow, right?
切り替えて。
Switch gears.
切り替えていくか。
Switching gears, I guess?
いや、もう本当にありがとう。
But seriously, thank you so much.
嬉しい。
I'm so happy.
めちゃめちゃ頼んだの、「会いに行きたい」って。
We pleaded so much, saying we wanted to see you.
そうなの？
Really?
もう、一人でなんか勝手に色んなもの背負ってさ。
You were trying to carry everything by yourself again.
やめて、行くなんて許せない。
Don't you dare think you can just go, we won't allow it.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
頼ってよ、もっと。頼りなよ。
Rely on us more. Depend on us.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ということでもう、ちょっと無理を言って、今日駆け付けさせていただきました。
So, we made a selfish request and rushed here today.
本当に、本当に、本当にすごいこと。
This is really, really, really an amazing thing.
ありがとうね。
Thank you.
最後まで見てるから。
We'll watch you until the end.
行っちゃうの？
Are you leaving already?
行かないよ！お前が行くんだよ！お前が行くんだよ！
No, we're not! You're the one who's going! You're going!
お前が先に行くんだ。
You are the one who's going.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
行かない、見てるからね。
We're not going anywhere, we're watching.
頑張ってね、最後まで。
Do your best, until the very end.
まだ泣かないよ、まだあるから。
Don't cry yet, there's still more.
追い焚きしてきてるのね、今、本当に。
You're really hyping me up, seriously.
頼むよ。
We're counting on you.
ありがとう。頑張る。ありがとうね。これからもずっと仲良くしてください。
Thank you. I'll do my best. Thank you. Please continue to be good friends with me.
当たり前だよ。一生友達だよね。
Of course! We're friends for life!
ずっと友達、ずっとこれからも。
Friends forever, from now on too.
縁側で語り明かそうね、おばあちゃんになっても。
Let's talk all night on the porch, even when we become old grandmas.
そこ（特等席）で見てるから。
We'll be watching from there.
ありがとう。大好きだぞ！
Thank you. We love you!
頑張ってね！
Do your best!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
またね！
See you!
今回、みんなに説明した感じで、ゲストは今回は呼べないけど頑張るって言ったんですけど、
I told everyone that I wouldn't have any guests today and that I would do my best alone, but...
コロさんとあずちゃんとラミィが来てくれました。
Koro-san, Azu-chan, and Lamy came for me.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
それでは、ここからオリジナル楽曲が続いていきます。
Well then, from here, my original songs will continue.
歌えるのは、最後になってしまうんですが、だからこそ、たくさんの思い出を思い出しながら、
This will be the last time I get to sing them, which is why, remembering so many memories,
心を込めて歌っていこうと思います。
I will sing with all my heart.
ちょっと、本当にびっくりした。本当にありがとう。
I was really surprised. Thank you so much.
本当に素晴らしい友達を持って幸せです。ホロライブに入れてよかった。
I am so happy to have such wonderful friends. I am glad I joined Hololive.
ということで、じゃあ、聴いてね！
With that said, please listen!
きゅーぴっど。
[Song: Cupid. | Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: TeddyLoid]
きみはきゅーぴっどです むーがむちゅー ちゅーちゅー
You are Cupid, completely obsessed with you, chu chu
きっと夢にでてくる ちゅーちゅーちゅー
You'll surely appear in my dreams, chu chu chu
ちゅーちゅーちゅー ちゅーちゅーちゅー ちゅーちゅーちゅー
Chu chu chu, chu chu chu, chu chu chu
ぎゅっと 抱きしめて
Hold me tight
意図しない着信音 やだやだやだやだ
Unintended ringtone, no no no no
どうせソシャゲのログイン通知
Anyway, it's just a notification to log in to a gacha game
やだやだやだやだ
No no no no
誰かが待ってるエレベーター やだやだやだやだ
Someone waiting in the elevator, no no no no
そう、我らこそ 陰の者
Yes, we are indeed introverts!
笑おう笑おう せめて笑おう あははは
Let's laugh, let's laugh, at least let's laugh, ahaha
なるほどです！
I see!
来ない来ない 空回り
No invitations coming, spinning my wheels
反省反省 また反省だ
Reflecting, reflecting, reflecting again
鏡すらも 目をそらした
Even the mirror turned its eyes away
明日は今日より 人間になりたい なりたい なりたい なりたい！
Tomorrow, I want to be more human than today, I want to, I want to, I want to!
おやすみさ！
Good night!
DA・LI・LA
[Song: DA・LI・LA | Lyrics, Composition: Hitomi Sano | Arrangement: Misato Tsuchiya]
不安が膨らむわ パフォーマンス
Anxiety swells up, performance
目の前の私 ちっとも足りないじゃないの
The me in front of you isn't enough at all
幕が上がる 準備はいいかい そうね
The curtain rises. Are you ready? Yes, indeed...
ここでしょうね
Right here, isn't it?
あなたに捧げるわ
I will dedicate to you...
私の愛と やれるすべて
...all of my love and everything I can do.
この手は私を守るため
These hands were meant to protect me...
あったのね
...weren't they?
ついでに君と喰うわ
And while I'm at it, I'll eat you up.
どんなさようならをご希望？
What kind of farewell would you prefer?
ラストはうんと飾らなきゃ
The end must be heavily decorated!
足りない 足りないだって 足りない 少しだけ
Not enough, not enough, it's not enough, just a little more.
DA・LI・LA 頭も綺麗
DA-LI-LA, even my mind is beautiful.
[十万億土]
[Title: Jyuuman Okudo]
さあ一丁 抜け駆けしなはれ 皆天晴れ
Now then, get ahead of the crowd! Bravo to everyone!
重ねど劣等 留めてポウ
Piling up inferiorities, freeze and strike a pose!
天の賽は投げられたのでしょう
The celestial dice must have already been cast.
さよう さよう どいつもこいつも
Indeed, indeed, every single one of them...
手遅れさ 限りあるこちらへおいでよ<
...is too late. Come over here, to this limited world!
鏡よ その人はだあれ
Oh mirror, who is that person?
恐れず僕と歌おう
Sing with me without fear.
ぱぱぱのぱぱぱ
Pa-pa-pa-no-pa-pa-pa
巡り巡れよ 獄卒しよう
Spinning round and round, let's be prison wardens of hell!
そろそろ終わりにしないか
Isn't it about time to bring this to an end?
今ならば美しい ほら
If it's right now, it would be beautiful. Look!
君は今更 戻れない
You can no longer turn back now.
[別世界]
[Title: Another World]
愛してくれ 僕のことも
Please love me too,
どうか邪魔などしないから
I promise I won't get in your way.
遠い遠い別世界まで
Even to a far, far different world...
袖触れないままに 幕が上がる
Without our sleeves ever touching, the curtain rises.
ただ また会いたくて
I just wanted to see you again,
あなたにこの拍手を
I offer this applause to you.
[Knock it out!]
[Title: Knock it out!]
無敵な愛！ 愛！ 愛！ 愛！ 愛だ！
Invincible love! Love! Love! Love! It's love!
着飾れほら シーツ 憂鬱 クローゼット
Dress up, look, sheets, melancholy, closet!
ない！ ない！ ない！ 君はないな
No! No! No! You've got nothing!
ハッシュタグ ショータイム 壊せプライド
Hashtag, showtime, destroy your pride!
[おらくる]
[Title: Oracle]
あらあら、もうそんな傷つけたりしないで
Oh dear, please don't hurt them like that anymore.
こんなバグだらけの世界になっちゃって、ごめんね<
I'm sorry this world ended up so full of bugs.
大丈夫、安全圏に居よね
It's alright, let's stay in the safety zone.
不完全な世界に来よね 見捨てないからずっと今日も
Come to this incomplete world. I won't abandon you, ever, even today.
あら、あら、あら、神を騙りて、ただの希望に成れ
Oh, oh, oh, impersonate God and become a mere hope.
人道的な線になるまで愛してあげるね
I'll love you until it becomes a humane boundary.
混沌で満たして 理不尽に恋焦がして
Fill it with chaos, yearn for the unreasonable.
忘れちゃうくらい 笑っちゃうくらい ちゃんと愛、愛、愛、ラヴユー
So much you forget, so much you laugh, properly love, love, love, love you!
[Last-resort]
[Title: Last-resort]
ただ息を潜め 音は立てるな
Just hold your breath, don't make a sound...
奴らに気付かれる前に
...before they notice you.
鉄の目を殺し その時を待て
Kill your metal eyes and wait for the moment.
すべては一瞬のために<
Everything is for that single instant.
ラスト・リゾートは今
The last resort is now!
カリスマの前でアイドルのショー
An idol's show in front of a charisma.
奇跡をぶち抜け ラスト・リゾート
Break through the miracle, last resort!
トリックのなさそうな壊滅の世界で
In a ruined world with seemingly no tricks,
死に物狂いのラスト・リゾート
a desperate, life-or-death last resort!
刹那、泣き崩れ、すべてを壊し
At that moment, breaking down in tears, destroying everything,
この一瞬に賭けて放つラストリゾート
Betting everything on this single instant, unleashing my last resort!
僕のすべてを込めて放つラストリゾート
With all of myself poured in, unleashing my last resort!
[片羽]
[Title: Single Wing]
あなたがくれた希望で
With the hope you gave me,
約束の羽で今
with the promised wings, right now...
片羽でもいい 共に往こう
Even with a single wing, let us go together...
地平の先へ
...to the end of the horizon.
壊れるまで遠く遠くへ
Far, far away, until we break.
不器用な僕らは 片翼でいい
Clumsy as we are, a single wing is enough.
飛べるよ 信じて 飛べるよ その先へ 飛べるよ
We can fly, believe it, we can fly, to what lies ahead, we can fly!
楽園 永遠の
Paradise... eternal...
届くその時まで
until the moment we reach it.
あー
Ah...
きっと掴んでみせるよ
I will definitely seize it.
あー
Ah...
遙か彼方と 待ってて
In the far beyond... wait for me.
思い出して 出会った日のこと
I remember the day we first met.
手をとって僕らの旅が始まった
Taking your hand, our journey began.
走って 転んで 涙を流しても
Even when running, falling, and shedding tears,
気がつけば ほら 顔合わせて笑う
before I knew it, look, we laughed face to face.
喜びの声が嬉しくて 夢が溢れ出すね
Hearing your voices of joy makes me so happy, my dreams overflow.
君がいなきゃダメなんだ
It has to be you.
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now,
世界で一番の笑顔をあげちゃう
I'm going to give you the best smile in the world!
僕を見つけてくれた 愛してくれた
You found me and you loved me,
だから まだまだ終わらない ちゃんとついてきて
so this is far from over! Keep up with me,
きらめく夢
in this glittering dream.
羽ばたいていく 背中を見送った
I watched your back as you flew away.
雨上がり 君の傘を返したら
Once the rain stops and I return your umbrella,
手を引いて進もう 一緒にどこまでも
let's hold hands and move forward, together wherever we go.
気がつけば ほら また前を向ける
Before I knew it, look, I can look forward again.
じゃれ合う言葉の中にも 愛を感じています
Even in our playful banter, I can feel your love.
僕じゃなきゃダメなんでしょう？でしょう？
It has to be me, right? Right?
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now,
世界で一番のときめきをあげちゃう
I'm going to give you the greatest excitement in the world!
僕を支えてくれた 推してくれた
You supported me and cheered for me,
だから まだまだ終わらない 隣にいてよ
so this is far from over! Stay by my side.
Oh...
自信なんか無い 不安ばかりだ
I have no confidence, only anxieties.
「もうやめよう」って泣いた日もあった
There were days I cried, saying, "I want to quit."
そんな時浮かんでくるの みんなの声が
At times like those, everyone's voices come to my mind.
今までで一番諦めたくないの
This is the one thing I don't want to give up on.
ずっと成りたかった最強のアイドル
The strongest idol I've always wanted to be.
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now,
世界で一番の大好きをあげちゃう
I'm going to give you the biggest "I love you" in the world!
些細な日常も もっと大きなステージへ
Taking even our mundane daily lives to an even bigger stage.
まだまだ終われない ありふれた奇跡を
This is far from over! An ordinary miracle...
君と結んでいく
...I'll weave together with you.
行け！
Go!
はい！はい！
Yeah! Yeah!
生む意志
The will to live...
おりゃ！走！
Hah! Run!
痛みに悶えて本気改正を
Writhe in pain and get a real revision!
ボリューム、バキ！
Volume up, snap!
手にする全部
Everything I get my hands on,
It's mine くるくる
it's mine, spinning around,
テキトーに頑張ろうか
shall we try our best in a relaxed way?
そんなんだっていいけどさ
That's fine too, but...
必死に頑張ろうか それが僕らしさだ
...let's try with all our might! That's just like me.
おささげじゃないんだわ とんでもぴんぼっちじゃないんだわ
It's not a sacrifice! I'm definitely not a sad, lonely person!
うん パンチがバッチリ イケてるに決まってる
Yeah, my punch is perfectly cool, without a doubt!
かなたちゃん！
Kanata-chan!
テンション 情緒 ちゃんと歓迎して
Welcome your high tension and emotions properly!
高まる解放 想像 ちゃんと協調して
Coordinate properly with your rising release and imagination!
興奮しよう
Let's get excited!
僕がよわんだもん
Because I'm weak...
ホッとするんだもん
...and want to feel at ease...
現実超え選ぶ未来を
...in the future I choose that transcends reality.
弱点も兵器 スイッチ入れちゃえ
Even my weaknesses are weapons! Turn the switch on!
進むのは 特者生存ワンダラダーって
We are moving forward because we're the survivors on this "Wander-ladder"!
楽しもう
Let's enjoy it!
面白がれること 探し求めて
Let's search for things we can find fun...
返事聞かせてくれ
...let me hear your answer!
右？left？ どっちでもない
Right? Left? It's neither!
突き抜けていこう 一直線
Let's break right through, in a straight line!
つまりたくらむなら 発車オーライだ
If you're plotting something, we are good to go!
ワクワクするでしょ？
You're excited, aren't you?
聞いて！みんなと離れるのが寂しいのと 佳希の結婚から立ち直ってません！
Listen! I'm sad to be leaving everyone, and I still haven't recovered from Kaki's marriage!
僕をアイドルにしてくれて みんな本当にありがとう！
Thank you all so much for making me an idol!
なんだよ そんなこと言っちゃダメだ おバカ！
What is that? You shouldn't say things like that, silly!
わあ、すごい！ありがとう！
Wow, amazing! Thank you!
Keep it up! そう、全力で
Keep it up! Yes, with all our might...
Go my way!
虎視眈々でいたいだもん
Because I want to stay vigilant...
だってイケイケでいいだもん
...because it's fine to go all out!
全方位にがっつり お手手振っていらっしゃい
Wave your hands to all directions!
いつでも心はちゃんと純粋で
My heart is always pure and genuine!
いろいろな好奇心は 大事にして
Let's cherish all kinds of curiosity!
「一斉に」って言い聞かせるんだ
I tell myself "all together!"...
調子に乗ったら すぐ飽きられちゃうから
...because if I get carried away, people will get bored of me soon!
回答なロボット 解いてみせて
Try to solve this answered robot!
進むのは 特者生存ワンダラダーって
We are moving forward because we're the survivors on this "Wander-ladder"!
仕込み続け
Keep preparing...
努力とは 最後まで諦めないこと
...because effort means not giving up until the very end.
メモっておいて
Make a note of that!
本当はベビー 自信がないよ
Honestly, baby, I have no confidence.
本当はベビー 不安ばかりで泣きそうだって
Honestly, baby, I'm so full of anxiety that I feel like crying.
お願いベビー くじけないって決めたの
Please, baby, I've decided not to get discouraged.
だからベビー
So baby...
挑戦したいんだ 未開の天地
...I want to challenge unexplored lands...
無限のフィールドで
...in an infinite field!
テンション 情緒 ちゃんと歓迎して
Welcome your high tension and emotions properly!
高まる解放 想像 ちゃんと協調して
Coordinate properly with your rising release and imagination!
興奮しよう
Let's get excited!
僕がよわんだもん
Because I'm weak...
ホントにするんだもん
...and want to make it real...
現実超え選ぶ未来を
...in the future I choose that transcends reality.
弱点も兵器 スイッチ入れちゃえ
Even my weaknesses are weapons! Turn the switch on!
進むのは 特者生存ワンダラダーって
We are moving forward because we're the survivors on this "Wander-ladder"!
楽しもう
Let's enjoy it!
面白がれること 探し放題です
We can search for fun things as much as we want!
無限のフィールドね
It's an infinite field, right?
パニングしなくてもいい
You don't even have to pan!
ど真ん中いっちゃって
Go straight through the middle!
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
In short, this is my answer!
胸を張れ
Hold your head high!
今を生きるその意味を
The meaning of living in the present...
明くる日も明くる日も確かめて
...I'll confirm it day after day...
進めワンダラー！
...and move forward, wanderer!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
みんな、ありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much!
はい、えー聞いていただいたのは、オリ曲メドレー、メドレーにしました。
Yes! Um, what you just heard was an original song medley. I made it a medley!
繋ぎましたよ！
I chained them together!
そして「世界で一番のアイドル」、作詞をしました。
And "Sekai de Ichiban no Idol", which I wrote the lyrics for.
この時、卒業だって考えてなかったから。
Back then, I wasn't even thinking about graduating,
本当に、あの、いっぱい聞いてほしい曲です。
so it's a song I really want you to listen to a lot.
そして、「特者生存ワンダラダー!!」でした！
And that was "Tokusha Seizon Wander-la-der!!"!
はい、これを初めてね、出したね。
Yes, this was the first time I performed it, right?
えー、オリジナル楽曲ですけれど。
It's an original song.
ちょっと語りたいこといっぱいあるんですけど。
There's actually so much I want to talk about, but...
やっぱりあの服だよね？ってことで、1秒着替えしてきました！
...you're probably waiting for that outfit, right? So I did a one-second outfit change!
はい！
Yes!
やっぱこれだよね、みんな！
It has to be this one, right, everyone?
はい、こんかなたー！
Yes! Kon-kanata!
キャッチコピーは握力50キロ、ギューギュー握り潰しちゃうぞ、ホロライブ4期生、かなたんこと天音かなたです！
My catchphrase is: "With a grip strength of 50 kg, I'll squeeze and crush you!" I'm Hololive 4th Gen, Kanatan, also known as Amane Kanata!
はい、ということでね、あのー、危ないことはね、危ない橋は渡らないでおきまして。
Yes! And so, I decided not to cross any dangerous bridges...
あのようなね、感じでいきたいと思うんですけれど。
...and I'd like to continue in that kind of style.
もう本当にオリジナル楽曲はね、フェスやイベント、ソロライブなど、他にもたくさんの思い出が詰まっていて。
But really, my original songs are filled with so many memories from festivals, events, solo concerts, and more.
みんながね、たくさん聴いてくれたおかげと言いますか
Thanks to everyone listening to it so much...
本当にありがとうございます、と思っています
Thank you so much. That's what I truly feel.
みんなね、あの...
Everyone, um...
このあとですね、あの、22時20分から
After this, at 22:20...
最後の歌ってみた、みんなと約束してました
...the last cover song I promised you all...
動画消えちゃって歌い直そうって言っていた、あの
...the one where the video went down and I said I'd re-sing it...
「KING」を投稿するので、絶対見てくださいね！
I'll be uploading "KING", so please make sure to watch!
毎日一緒にいてくれたへい民、ホロライブの大好きなメンバーたち
To the Heimin who stayed with me every day, and my beloved Hololive members,
そして、たくさん支えてくださった、本当にお世話になった方々、すべての方に感謝しています
and to everyone who supported and took great care of me, I thank you all.
夢のような時間を本当にありがとうございました
Thank you so much for this dream-like time.
こども、ここ、ここで噛むね（笑）、子供の頃のアイドルになりたいという夢が
My... I stuttered there (laughs). My childhood dream of becoming an idol,
作詞作曲をしてみたいという夢も、叶いました！
and my dream of writing and composing songs, have both come true!
そして、最後の曲ですが
And now, for the final song...
まだ歌うんですよ！
I'm still going to sing!
僕が初めて作詞作曲した楽曲があります
There is a song that I wrote and composed for the first time.
今はいない同期、ココの卒業に合わせて、4期生の
For the graduation of Coco, a Gen 4 member who is no longer here,
トワ、ルーナ、わために捧げた楽曲です
...a song dedicated to Towa, Luna, and Watame.
前を向いて笑顔で、この楽曲で活動を最後にしたいと思います
I want to end my activities with this song, looking forward with a smile.
それでは聴いてください。「キセキ結び」
Please listen. "Kiseki Musubi".
約束しようよ
Let's make a promise,
僕ら出会えたキセキ
so that the miracle of our meeting
忘れないように
won't ever be forgotten.
夢抱いて集う
Gathering with dreams in our hearts,
青春アニメみたいな
like a youth anime.
ハッピーなエンドになる かなたへ飛ぶよ
We'll fly toward the distance for a happy ending.
寝ぼけ眼 あくびして
Rubbing our sleepy eyes and yawning,
今日は何をしようか
what shall we do today?
永遠に続く海を駆けるケルン
The cairn running across the endless sea.
今はため息よりも勇気を
Right now, give me courage rather than sighs.
諦めるなんてないの ここで歌う
There's no giving up, I will sing right here.
僕の声は聴こえていますか
Can you hear my voice?
君に届け
Let it reach you!
学校の友達じゃきっと出会えなかった
We'd never have met if we were just school friends.
カレンダーの先の遥か遠くまで
To the far-off future beyond the calendar...
囁いてくれた言葉が
The words you whispered to me
誰かの笑顔になれる
can bring a smile to someone's face.
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ奇跡
A miracle of linking stars with each of our colors,
キラキラ輝くステージに
to the sparkling stage,
連れてくよ
I will take you.
泣いて笑ってはしゃいで
Crying, laughing, and fooling around,
毎日ジェットコースター
every day is a roller coaster.
たまには寝転んでお昼寝しよう
Sometimes let's just lie down and take a nap.
ちょっとしんどいとき こっそりハイタッチして
When things are a bit tough, we quietly high-five.
今日だけは泣いちゃうこと許してね
Forgive me for crying just for today.
未来の僕が
In the future,
アルバム開く
when I open the album,
傷ついた写真だって宝物だ
even the damaged photos will be treasures.
僕の愛は見えていますか
Can you see my love?
君に届け
Let it reach you!
過去も個性も性格も違うけれど
Though our pasts, personalities, and characters differ,
弱気な時は目蓋ギュッと瞑り
when you're feeling weak, close your eyes tight.
もう一回もう一回 絶対に諦めない
One more time, one more time, never giving up!
前を歩く背中追う
Chasing the back of the one walking ahead,
下手っぴな僕でも
even if I'm clumsy,
君の隣にいたくて
Because I want to be by your side,
走るの
I run.
誰にも言えずに描いた夢が
Even if the dream I drew in secret
たとえ叶わないとしても
never comes true,
ボロボロの靴でもかっこよくなくても
even in tattered shoes, even if I'm not cool,
お揃い あの日の僕ならなんて言う？
matching... what would the "me" of that day say?
止まらないで
Don't stop!
初めて僕ら出会った日
The day we first met,
まるで昨日のように思い出すけど
I remember it as if it were yesterday,
もう行こうか
but shall we go now?
最後に今
At last, now,
重なる
we overlap.
僕の声は聴こえていますか
Can you hear my voice?
君に届け
Let it reach you!
黒板のメッセージ 桜の風送って
A message on the blackboard, sending a cherry blossom breeze,
僕らの声を聞いて ずっとずっと
listen to our voices, forever and ever.
嬉しい日 楽しい日
悲しい日 別れの日も
Joyful days, fun days,
sad days, and even days of parting...
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ奇跡
With our respective colors,
it's a miracle that connects the stars.
キラキラ輝くステージで
On this sparkling, shining stage,
約束しよう
let's make a promise.
いつかここで また会おう
Let's meet here again someday.
おわる！ありがとう！
It's ending! Thank you!
ホロライブ4期生、アイドルの天音かなたでした！
This was Hololive's 4th Gen idol, Amane Kanata!
4年間本当に幸せな日々でした！
These past four years were truly happy days!
へいみん、不器用な僕を応援してくれてありがとう！
Heymin, thank you for supporting clumsy me!
ずっとずっと大好きだよ！
I will love you forever and ever!
ずっとずっと家族だよ！
We will be family forever and ever!
みんな本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so, so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!